DANILA RASSOKHIN

Yerevan, Armenia (ready to relocate)

danilarassokhin@gmail.com • Telegram: @RassokhinD • https://linkedin.com/in/danilarassokhin

SUMMARY

Java/Kotlin developer with over 3 years of experience building and maintaining applications using Spring Boot, Hibernate, Camunda, Postgres, Kafka and related technologies. I have improved application performance and reduced errors, and I've helped make development processes more efficient. I share my knowledge through mentoring, technical interviews, writing about Java, Spring, and Postgres on Medium. I'm looking for a challenging Java Backend Engineer role where I can use my skills to work on important projects. I am ready to relocate or work remotely.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YLAB

Middle Java/Kotlin Developer | NDA (Large metallurgy enterprise)

Aug 2023 - Present

- Optimized the image generation process, resulting in a 20% reduction in RAM usage, leading to improved Spring application stability and reduced server costs
- Implemented image compression using ImageIO, preserving original aspect ratio; This resulted in a 30% reduction of S3 bucket size and lower storage costs
- Replaced Jasper Reports with Apache POI for Excel report generation, resulting in a 10% increase in report generation speed
- Introduced Camunda BPMN schemas testing, reducing runtime bugs by 60%
- Developed Kotlin-based testing utilities with a user-friendly DSL for Camunda, increasing test writing speed by 15% and boosting team's velocity by 5%
- Achieved 100% test coverage for two large BPMN schemas, comprising over 700 elements and 1100 flows
- Designed user-friendly utilities and 3 load testing scenarios using JavaScript and K6
- Enhanced team efficiency through a new practice, resulting in 1-2 additional closed business tasks per sprint
- Performed code reviews for over 100 interns in an internal Java course and conducted more than 20 interviews.

YLAB

Junior Java Developer | NDA (Billing system)

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Covered 7 BPMN schemas for Camunda with integration tests, resulting in improved stability
- Achieved test coverage of 97% for 6 Spring microservices using unit tests and integration tests

YLAB

Junior Java Developer | NDA (Electronic document management)

SEP 2022 - May 2023

- Designed and developed a BPMN migration tool, similar to Liquibase, that accelerated development by 10%
- Created a REST connector for Camunda 8 for distributed logging and reduced error investigation time by 10%
- Created a job worker for Camunda 8 to enable uploading and downloading files from S3 within BPMN tasks
- Redesigned the search functionality over Elasticsearch to support displaying over 10,000 documents

EDUCATION

KUBAN STATE UNIVERSITY

Krasnodar, Russia

Master of Informatics And Applied Mathematics

2022-2024

Studied computer science. Participated in several conferences and authored papers on cryptography and bioinformatics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java, Kotlin
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Hibernate, JOOQ, Camunda, gRPC
- Databases and platforms: Postgres, Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch, Redis, S3
- Tools: Docker, CI/CD, Apache Avro, Jasper Reports, Flyway, Liquibase
- System design: Microservices, REST API, Gateway, Reactive, LDAP
- Languages: Russian (native), English (B2)